At GBT made this whole video with one image.
Here's exactly how step-by-step.
All right, so step one we're going to go into chat GBT and we're going to pick work,
not regular chat.
Reason why is because chat GBT work allows us to use our files and apps just a lot easier.
Now the second step we need is to create a main character.
So my main character is named Mani.
I made him early 30s, he's over six foot, he's Hispanic, he has a kind of a swag to him,
light skin, curly, all of that.
Now for your character, try to go as in detail as you can.
I'm talking about gender, race, age, height, what color he's wearing the far as his clothes,
all the details that you need, right?
I got a prompt for you to help you with that as well as going to create a character sheet for you.
The prompts and the step-by-step guide is going to be in the link in the description
as well on the QR code as about the pop-up.
Now that we have our main character, let's go into creating this video.
Now next thing we're going to do is upload our character sheet into chat GBT work if it's not
already created inside of there.
And we're just going to do kind of like a dead a dump, right?
I literally said I want to create a story and a storyboard image for an idea I have.
And I just kind of went no true structured prompt or anything like that.
I just went off the top of my dome and just was like, okay,
this is the story that I wanted.
Quick back story.
This is the second video that we did with Manny.
The first one we used to see Dan's 2.0 where he went to a rehab center to pick up his mom
and the mom wasn't there.
So this is the second part to it.
If you didn't see that video, I'll put it in the description as well and it'll pop up.
But this is a continuation.
So the brain dump was me explaining what the story was going to be
and that I needed character sheets on the two supporting characters.
I needed to create Manny's mom and I needed to create the street pharmacists.
So the brain dump was that the first scene was Manny kicking down the door.
The street pharmacist is right there kind of startled saying,
yo, this is not exactly what you think.
And then it shows the room where his mom is at.
There has a water and some pills and the mom looking kind of depressed.
And then Manny comes in.
So that was the data dump.
So once I press enter on the data dump, it made my storyboard exactly how I wanted it,
right? And always check the storyboard because if there's something messed up,
it will be messed up in your video.
So always get the storyboard first.
As well as it created the character sheets of Manny's mom and the street pharmacists.
And I created that because I'm going to need them for another video later on.
Be as detailed as you can with your story.
So ChatTBT doesn't kind of have to fill in the blanks because
we don't want to rely on AI to make the story for us just to help us.
Now, the next thing we're going to do is go into plugin and find HiggsField
because this is the tool that is going to give us the video right inside of ChatTBT.
Once you connect the plugin to ChatTBT,
it's going to ask you to log into your HiggsField account and then you're good to go.
Once we connect HiggsField, now it's time to take that storyboard
and turn it into a video.
So it's going to ask you to upload the character references and the storyboard.
If it doesn't automatically do that.
So I got a widget for it.
I uploaded it and then it started its process.
Now, quick tip.
Be very specific with what model you want and how many credits it's going to take.
For this example, we use cdance 2.5.
And once I asked it how many credits it's going to take, it said 98.
And it's good to ask because as you can see,
it originally wanted to do 30 seconds for 195 credits.
And I know I only wanted to make this into a 15 seconds one,
which was only going to take 98 credits.
Once we sorted all of that out, we got our first draft.
Let's play it.
All right, that's not bad.
Now, I had an issue with it.
If you saw the first couple of seconds, when he kicked the door, he kicked the door
the opposite way.
I would think you would kick the door in, not kick.
And then it comes out.
But that's just me.
And this is the last step of making the video inside of Chatchee BT,
which is tweak until you like it.
Now, as you can see in my conversations,
I don't talk to it like a prop structure.
I talk to it like a full-blown conversation.
And so there's going to be some tweaks that I'm going to make until I get it exactly.
And I realized that I had to be intentional
with the picture of the first frame because if not,
it's going to mess up the whole thing.
So let me go find where I actually got it right,
where boom, I actually had to make him like kick the door,
almost kick the door.
Not fully kicked the door, almost kicked the door,
door knob, all of that be very detailed with it.
And now we have the final product.
So let me know what you think.
Oh, hold on, Maddie, this isn't what you think it is.
Where is she?
Now, that was the process of how I made that video.
We went from creating a main character,
having a character sheet for that,
data dumping inside a Chatchee BT work,
creating not only the storyboard,
but also the character sheets of the supporting characters,
then we plugged in Higgsville,
and then we made the video tweaked it to finally get the final result.
Now, one of the sleeper tips that I don't know if you caught on to
is make sure you have your images right before it goes to video.
Never go from a data dump to just video.
Even though the video was created by that main storyboard,
you still want those character sheets.
You even still want to have maybe a separate picture
for the first frame if it doesn't go exactly the way you want it.
Now, one thing that I didn't show was a skill that I had already had
inside a Chatchee BT, which is a seed dance prompt skill.
This is going to help you take your data dump,
take the storyboard, and turn it into a seed dance prompt
that is read by Higgsville.
Now, my personal Chatchee BT skill that I use to make this video
is exclusively inside Alliance Behavior,
which is my private community, which link in the description.
But if you go back to that guy that I gave you,
there's going to be a prompt that will turn that data dump
into a seed dance ready prompt that will make your video.
You've probably been wondering what to do with Chatchee BT work.
Well, here's a great use case.
Let me know if you're going to use it.
And if you need another video about it, check it out here.